### **Justin Orlando**

757-916-5006 jorlandowork@gmail.com https://github.com/jnorlando

Computer Hardware Engineering

# **Summary**

My cumulative experience has provided me with the work ethic and commitment to service necessary to conquer any task provided. I am particularly good at communicating and framing new ideas. And enjoy collaborating on engineering tasks to come to the most effective solution. Though I have no problem working alone, putting my nose to the grindstone, and delving into a language to accomplish a particular goal, being that I have a passion for learning and loved programming since childhood, studying languages from Processing to Rust.

# Skills **Programming Languages:** Golang, C#, C++, Java, Javascript, Python, Ruby, Rust, Lua, Processing, SQL, HTML, CSS, Experience with Assembly Languages Frameworks: Asp.Net, React, Angular, Django Other: GORM, AXIOS, MAPBOX, JQUERY, JSON, TypeScript, LibGDX, Cheerio, LibCurl, Gumbo, libCPR **Other Utilities:** PhpmyAdmin, DBBeaver, Postman, Github, Docker, Android Development Studio, VS Code, VS Studio, Slack, Solar 2D **Key Expertise:** Software Design, SQL Database Development, Agile Development Practices Documentation, Onboarding, Public Relations, Art and Design Other Skills:

# Experience

## Full Stack Developer - The Clothing Loop

Responsibilities included: Developing web page layouts utilizing react app and type-script, making api calls via javascript to custom Golang functions, updating and designing a SQL database, researching new technology and utilities for development use, onboarding new personnel, attending weekly developer meetings and creating design documents.

December 2022 - Current

#### Media Representative - Americorps NCCC (North Central Region), Multi-State

Responsibilities included: completing 1700 hours of service with non-profits over a 10 month commitment, maintaining proper uniform and conducting oneself in a manner that reflects positively on the organization, being highly adaptable and multifaceted in order to complete a variety of unique projects in varying time frames, being highly team orientated and dependable (one works and lives with the save team over a term), and completing specialization paperwork such as press releases, presentations, and media posts in a timely manner.

February 2018 - November 2018

#### Transporter I - University of Virginia Medical System

A transporter provides safe transport of the right patient to the right location while maintaining a high level of productivity as well as delivering blood or plasma in crisis situations. Other responsibilities include: distributing equipment and supplies, morgue duties, and mentoring, Services are provided to patients, visitors, and health care staff twenty-four hours/day seven days a week.

July 2017 - January 2018

## Education

Tidewater Community College - A.S Computer Science (2022-Current)

Fluvanna County High School, Fluvanna, VA - High School Diploma (2016)

## **Certificates and Awards**

- ASP.NET for Experienced Developers Specialization, Board Infinity
- Managing Big Data with MySQL, Duke University
- Business Metrics For Data-Driven Companies, Duke University
- Agile Project Management, Google
- Completion of coursework in software and computer hardware engineering
- Graduation Certificate (for completing 10 month commitment and 1700+ hours service) Americorps NCCC acting as credit towards a masters in nonprofit management.

# **Projects**

- Developed a fintech application using Django and Jazzmin allowing for payments to be received and sent from a sqlite server
- Developed a portfolio website utilizing Django, Bootstrap, and Sqlite
- Developed a basic blogsite with basic CRUD feature implementation with C# and ASP.NET